the story of the billy possum was all wrong, especially compared to the backstory of the teddy bear. Think about it: for most of human's evolutionary history, what's made bears impressive to us has been their complete independence from us. It's that they live these parallel lives as menaces and competitors. By the time Roosevelt went hunting in Mississippi, that stature was being crushed, and the animal that he had roped to a tree really was a symbol for all bears. Whether those animals lived or died now was entirely up to the compassion or the indifference of people. That said something really ominous about the future of bears, but it also said something very unsettling about who we'd become, if the survival of even an animal like that was up to us now. So now, a century later, if you're at all paying attention to what's happening in the environment, you feel that discomfort so much more intensely. We're living now in an age of what scientists have started to call "conservation reliance," and what that term means is that we've disrupted so much that nature can't possibly stand on its own anymore, and most endangered species are only going to survive if we stay out there in the landscape riggging the world around them in their favor. So we've gone hands-on and we can't ever take our hands off, and that's a hell of a lot of work. Right now, we're training condors not to perch on power lines. We teach whooping cranes to migrate south for the winter behind little ultra-light airplanes. We're out there feeding plague vaccine to ferrets. We monitor pygmy rabbits with drones. So we've gone from annihilating species to micromanaging the survival of a lot of species indefinitely, and which ones? Well, the ones that we've told compelling stories about, the ones we've decided ought to stick around. The line between conservation and domestication is blurred. So what I've been saying is that the stories that we tell about wild animals are so subjective they can be irrational or romanticized or sensationalized. Sometimes they just have nothing to do with the facts. But in a world of conservation reliance, those stories have very real consequences, because now, how we feel about an animal affects its survival more than anything that you read about in ecology textbooks. Storytelling matters now. Emotion matters. Our imagination has become an ecological force. And so maybe the teddy bear worked in part because the legend of Roosevelt and that bear in Mississippi was kind of like an allegory of this great responsibility that society was just beginning to face up to back then. It would be another 71 years before the Endangered Species Act was passed, but really, here's its whole ethos boiled down into something like a scene you'd see in a stained glass window. The bear is a helpless victim tied to a tree, and the president of the United States decided to show it some mercy. Thank you. (Applause) [Illustrations by Wendy MacNaughton]
la historia de la zarigüeya Billy estuvo mal, sobre todo en comparación con la historia de fondo del oso de peluche. Piensen en esto: para gran parte de la historia de la evolución humana, lo que nos resulta impresionante de los osos es su total independencia de nosotros. Es que ellos viven esas vidas paralelas como amenazas y competidores. Cuando Roosevelt fue de caza a Mississippi, esa imagen estaba siendo aplastada, y el animal que estaba atado a un árbol era un símbolo de todos los osos. Que esos animales vivieran o murieran dependía totalmente de la compasión o de la indiferencia de las personas. Eso decía algo realmente malo sobre el futuro de los osos, pero también decía algo muy inquietante sobre nosotros, incluso la supervivencia de un animal así ahora dependía de nosotros. Así que ahora, un siglo más tarde, si acaso prestan atención a lo que sucede en el ambiente, uno siente el malestar mucho más intensamente. Estamos viviendo una época que los científicos empiezan a llamar "dependencia de conservación", y eso significa que hemos devastado tanto, que la naturaleza quizá ya no pueda valerse por sí sola y las especies más amenazadas solo van a sobrevivir si permanecemos en el paisaje amarrando el mundo circundante en su favor. Hemos metido mano y ya no podemos sacarla, y eso requiere muchísimo trabajo. En estos momentos, estamos entrenando cóndores para que no se posen en los tendidos eléctricos. Enseñamos a las grullas blancas a emigrar hacia el sur para el invierno detrás de pequeños aviones ultraligeros. Estamos ahí vacunando contra la peste de los hurones. Hacemos seguimiento de conejos pigmeos con drones. Hemos pasado de aniquilar especies a la microgestión de la supervivencia de muchas especies por tiempo indefinido, y ¿cuáles son? Bueno, esas de las que hemos contado historias convincentes, de las que hemos decidido que deberían quedarse. La línea entre la conservación y la domesticación es borrosa. Así que lo que he estado diciendo es que las historias que contamos sobre los animales salvajes son tan subjetivas que pueden ser irracionales, románticas o sensacionalistas. A veces no tienen nada que ver con los hechos. Pero en un mundo de dependencia de conservación, esas historias tienen consecuencias muy reales, porque ahora, la manera de sentir a un animal afecta su supervivencia más que cualquier cosa que uno lea sobre ecología en los libros. Ahora importa la narrativa. Importa la emoción. Nuestra imaginación se ha convertido en una fuerza ecológica. Quizá el oso de peluche funcionó en parte debido a la leyenda de Roosevelt y aquella osa de Mississippi fue como una alegoría de esta gran responsabilidad que la sociedad estaba empezando a enfrentar en ese entonces. Pasarían otros 71 años antes de que se aprobara la Ley de Especies en Peligro de Extinción, pero, en realidad, aquí está todo su ethos reducido a algo así como una escena que uno vería en un vitral. El oso es una víctima indefensa atada a un árbol, y el presidente de Estados Unidos decidió mostrar un poco de misericordia. Gracias. (Aplausos) [Ilustraciones de Wendy MacNaughton]